<?xml version="1.0"?>
<!--
    "type" attribute can be: add, remove, update or fix. 
-->
<document>
    <properties>
        <title>Changes</title>
        <author email="fgiust(at)users.sourceforge.net">Fabrizio Giustina</author>
    </properties>
    <body>
        <release version="1.0" date="January 1, 2005" description="1.0 happynewyear release">
            <action type="fix" dev="fgiust">
                Fixed some remaining https issues when saving exported files in Internet Explorer with the export filter
                enabled.
            </action>
            <action type="fix" dev="fgiust" issue="DISPL-150">autolink working with https://, ftp://, etc.</action>
            <action type="fix" dev="fgiust" issue="DISPL-136">
                Column body is not rendered when requesting an invalid page.
            </action>
            <action type="fix" dev="fgiust" issue="DISPL-149">I18n Struts Adapter now works with Struts 1.1.</action>
            <action type="fix" dev="fgiust" issue="DISPL-156">
                Performance optimization: reduce the use of temporary StringBuffers while building the html table.
            </action>
            <action type="fix" dev="fgiust" issue="DISPL-148">Sporadic error with factory.requestHelper.</action>
            <action type="add" dev="fgiust" issue="DISPL-144">
                DisplayTag is now able to load displaytag.properties from a different classloader (allows displaytag.jar
                to be placed in appserver shared libs).
            </action>
            <action type="fix" dev="fgiust" issue="DISPL-109">Center of paging banner number.</action>
            <action type="fix" dev="fgiust" issue="DISPL-145">Tag holding references to resources.</action>
            <action type="fix" dev="fgiust" issue="DISPL-142">
                Export of nested tables: now you can export the parent table without errors; nested tables are not
                included during export.
            </action>
        </release>
        <release version="1.0-rc2" date="November 19, 2004 " description="Final 1.0 release candidate">
            <action type="fix" dev="fgiust" issue="962448">
                getListIndex() in tableDecorator now correctly returns the index in the original list.
            </action>
            <action type="fix" dev="fgiust" issue="1006229" due-to="Konstantin">
                Proper encoding of URLs under JDK 1.4.
            </action>
            <action type="add" dev="rapruitt">
                Properties are looked up according to the locale of the request. More specific locales override more
                general locales on a key by key basis, so that, if a key is not present in the most specific locale file
                for a request, the tag will search through the more general files until the key is found.
            </action>
            <action type="fix" dev="fgiust" issue="1020948">NullpointerException in HeaderCell.</action>
            <action type="fix" dev="fgiust" issue="1016089">Param values not URLEncoded.</action>
            <action type="update" dev="fgiust" issue="DISPL-22">
                Exported output can now optionally be written directly (both with or without the export filter) and not
                buffered.
            </action>
            <action type="fix" dev="fgiust" issue="DISPL-21">Export filter not working in WebLogic.</action>
            <action type="add" dev="fgiust" issue="DISPL-13" due-to="Ivan Markov">
                Export system has been reworked, allowing registration of user-defined export views. A PDF export view
                has been added as an example (note that PDF export is not enabled by default in the distribution: you
                need to set the
                <code>export.pdf=true</code>
                config parameter and include the required libraries). Public APIs for export views have changed (a new
                interface has been added).
            </action>
            <action type="fix" dev="fgiust" issue="DISPL-12">
                Algorithm in org.displaytag.util.ParamEncoder produces easily colliding keys.
            </action>
            <action type="add" dev="fgiust" issue="DISPL-35">
                Enable / disable param forwarding. A new
                <code>excludedParams</code>
                attribute has been added to the table tag, which allows you to specify the list of parameters which
                should not be forwarded during paging or sorting.
                <code>*</code>
                matches any parameter.
            </action>
            <action type="fix" dev="fgiust" issue="DISPL-53">
                The
                <code>titleKey</code>
                column attribute has been added to the standard version of the taglib too. The i18n support for titleKey
                has been refactored, adding a configurable resource provider which can wrap the localization support of
                any used frameworks (JSTL, Struts, Spring adapter are included, other can be added be users).
            </action>
            <action type="fix" dev="fgiust" issue="DISPL-15">display-el:column titleKey not Resin compatible.</action>
            <action type="fix" dev="fgiust" issue="DISPL-6">
                Error: mediaType is already defined. To avoid errors when nested tables are used, the current
                <code>mediaType</code>
                <strong>is no more declared as a compile-time variable</strong>
                . This means that you can still retrieve the current media type using
                <code>pageContext.getAttribute("mediaType")</code>
                but not using a scriptlet like
                <code>
                    <![CDATA[<%=mediaType%>]]>
                </code>
                . If you previously used this sintax you will have to fix your jsps when upgrading to 1.0 rc2.
            </action>
            <action type="update" dev="fgiust">
                The
                <code>name</code>
                attribute in the EL version of table Tag will now work both with EL expressions and with the "standard"
                displaytag sintax.
            </action>
            <action type="update" dev="fgiust" issue="DISPL-3">
                Column JSP body should only execute for rows being shown. Now column body is skipped if current row is
                not needed for display or sorting (be careful, if you sort the full list row need to be evaluated).
            </action>
            <action type="fix" dev="fgiust" issue="DISPL-9">Send user back to Page 1 on Desc/Asc.</action>
            <action type="add" dev="fgiust" issue="DISPL-26">
                More params for
                <code>paging.banner.*_items_found</code>
                .
            </action>
            <action type="fix" dev="fgiust" issue="DISPL-4">
                Html tags in "title" attribute when using maxLength.
            </action>
            <action type="fix" dev="fgiust" issue="DISPL-1">Autolink and maxlength problem.</action>
            <action type="fix" dev="fgiust" issue="DISPL-73" due-to="Mikko Wilkman">
                Unicode export with ResponseOverrideFilter fails because of improper content length setting.
            </action>
            <action type="update" dev="fgiust" issue="DISPL-2">
                Ability to use java var in id attribute in tabletag. A new
                <code>uid</code>
                attribute has been added for jsp 1.0 containers (look at the FAQ for more details).
            </action>
            <action type="add" dev="fgiust">
                New
                <code>htmlId</code>
                attribute which let you specify the value for the id attribute in the generated table.
            </action>
            <action type="add" dev="fgiust" issue="DISPL-106" due-to="Richard HALLIER">Webwork i18n support.</action>
            <action type="add" dev="fgiust" issue="DISPL-104">
                Need ability to disable prepending of context to the contents of the requestURI attribute. New
                <code>requestURIcontext</code>
                table attribute added.
            </action>
            <action type="add" dev="fgiust" issue="DISPL-81">Using ColumnDecorator with tag body.</action>
            <action type="add" dev="fgiust" issue="DISPL-58">
                New
                <code>sortProperty</code>
                attribute in column tag: specify property used for sorting.
            </action>
            <action type="update" dev="fgiust" issue="DISPL-117">
                Allow ColumnTag to generate links to current page.
            </action>
            <action type="update" dev="fgiust" issue="DISPL-112" due-to="Paul McCulloch">
                Allow requestURI with only parameters.
            </action>
            <action type="update" dev="fgiust" issue="DISPL-130">
                Allow column href also if paramId is not defined.
            </action>
        </release>
        <release version="1.0-rc1" date="July 11, 2004" description="1.0 release candidate.">
            <action type="fix" dev="fgiust">
                The EL version of the taglib has been refactored and cleaned up. All the attributes, except deprecated
                ones, now accept EL expressions.
            </action>
            <action type="fix" dev="fgiust" issue="927804">
                Improved attribute value handling following specifications for tag pooling. Should fix issues with
                Resin.
            </action>
            <action type="fix" dev="fgiust">
                Modified attribute type specification in tld to match setters in tag classes and added unit tests. Fixes
                validation issues with WebLogic 8.
            </action>
            <action type="fix" dev="fgiust" issue="926213">
                Added support for indexed/mapped properties in table decorators.
            </action>
            <action type="fix" dev="fgiust" issue="920115">MaxLength not working with double quotes.</action>
            <action type="add" dev="fgiust">
                New property
                <code>basic.msg.empty_list_row</code>
                which let you customize the message for an empty table while using
                <code>basic.empty.showtable = true</code>
                . This also allows you to customize the previously fixed "empty" css class.
            </action>
            <action type="fix" dev="fgiust" issue="895915">Export links are not shown for empty tables.</action>
            <action type="fix" dev="fgiust" issue="921811">
                ResponseOverrideFilter sets a bad contentType when charset is already specified.
            </action>
            <action type="fix" dev="fgiust" issue="938653">
                Reset headers during export. This allows export with https and should fix reported problems with Tomcat
                5.0.
            </action>
            <action type="fix" dev="fgiust" issue="944863">Wrong tfoot position.</action>
            <action type="fix" dev="fgiust" issue="842234">Fixed export.decorated property.</action>
            <action type="fix" dev="fgiust">
                Context path is automatically added to "requestURI" table attribute (only if link starts with "/").
            </action>
            <action type="fix" dev="fgiust" issue="894839">
                The "url" column attribute, already available in the EL version form 1.0-b3, has been moved to the
                standard library. The "url" attribute has the same meaning as the "href" attribute, but always prepends
                the context path to the URI.
            </action>
            <action type="fix" dev="fgiust" issue="952129">Column:autolink throwing exception or garbling urls.</action>
            <action type="fix" dev="fgiust" issue="944056" due-to="Sylvere Abbad">
                Pagination urls parameters wrong for multiple table on the same page.
            </action>
            <action type="fix" dev="fgiust" issue="947752">
                Unable to set the table "name" attribute in jsp 1.1 containers after release 1.0-b3 ("Unable to convert
                a String to java.lang.Object for attribute value" error).
            </action>
            <action type="fix" dev="fgiust" issue="958053">
                The export filter now only filters when needed. Response is not buffered when a special parameter
                inserted by displaytag in export links is not found.
            </action>
            <action type="fix" dev="fgiust" issue="968559">
                Export cancel out UTF8 filter. Now headers are not reset during an export request. Only headers which
                could prevent caching are overwritten.
            </action>
            <action type="fix" dev="fgiust">
                Automatic column discovery is turned off for Strings. Avoid displaying a single column "
                <code>Bytes</code>
                " when the source collection contains Strings.
            </action>
        </release>
        <release version="1.0-b3" date="April 12, 2004" description="last 1.0 beta">
            <action type="fix" dev="rapruitt">
                The export filter introduced in b2 has been modified to avoid errors in Websphere 4 (or in any j2ee 1.2
                containers, where the filter can't be used).
            </action>
            <action type="update" dev="fgiust">
                MediaTypeEnum has been moved to the org.displaytag.properties package. You will need to fix your imports
                if you started using with in the b2 release.
            </action>
            <action type="add" dev="fgiust" issue="851250">
                All the css classes in the table tag are now customizable. You can change the original
                <code>even, odd, sorted, order1, order2</code>
                classes and also configure a css class to be added to any table or to any sortable column.
            </action>
            <action type="add" dev="fgiust" issue="867217">
                Added the "defaultsort" attribute to change the sorting order for the default sorted column.
            </action>
            <action type="add" dev="fgiust">
                Added a new configuration property
                <code>basic.empty.showtable</code>
                which let you choose if you want to display the table if the underlining list is empty.
            </action>
            <action type="fix" dev="fgiust" issue="840728" due-to="David Kowis">Breaks on '%' in values.</action>
            <action type="fix" dev="fgiust" issue="849207">
                paramProperty is wrong when not fetched from iterated object.
            </action>
            <action type="fix" dev="fgiust" issue="858888">
                requestURI parameters are overwritten by current values.
            </action>
            <action type="add" dev="fgiust">Added the export.[exporttype].filename property.</action>
            <action type="fix" dev="fgiust" issue="882056">
                Export error - Filter not working (wrong constant name).
            </action>
            <action type="add" dev="fgiust" issue="887787">Added the "style" attribute to column tag.</action>
            <action type="fix" dev="rapruitt" issue="860387">
                Export filter was not preserving the locale setting.
            </action>
            <action type="fix" dev="rapruitt" issue="886495">Export filter failed under Weblogic; fixed.</action>
            <action type="fix" dev="fgiust" issue="897946">
                RequestURI attribute does not handle anchors ('#') properly.
            </action>
            <action type="fix" dev="fgiust" issue="873684">Sortable attribute not working.</action>
            <action type="add" dev="fgiust" issue="886050">
                Added a
                <code>caption</code>
                tag to display a table caption.
            </action>
            <action type="update" dev="fgiust">
                A new
                <code>org.displaytag.util.ParamEncoder</code>
                class has been added, to allow users to generate encoded parameter names like tabletag does.
                <strong>
                    Important! From now tables in the same pages which use the sorting, paging or exporting feature MUST
                    have a different ID
                </strong>
            </action>
            <action type="add" dev="fgiust">
                Added the new
                <code>sort.amount</code>
                configuration property.
            </action>
            <action type="update" dev="fgiust">
                Switching from Cactus to Servletunit tests. Servletunit tests resulted simpler to implement and more
                effective in testing tag output.
            </action>
            <action type="add" dev="fgiust">
                Test coverage reports added to the build. Free license for the displaytag project kindly donated by
                Clover.
            </action>
            <action type="fix" dev="fgiust" issue="891070">Two /tbody generated.</action>
            <action type="add" dev="fgiust">
                Support for arrays of Maps has been added in automatic column discovery. If you pass an array of map
                objects to the table tag the list of columns will be generated from the keys of the first map in the
                array. This allows to use the result of a jstl sql:query tag in a display:table without columns (use
                <code>
                    result
                    <strong>.rows</strong>
                </code>
                in the name attribute).
            </action>
            <action type="add" dev="mraible" due-to="Tim McCune">
                Added Expression Support ala JSTL. To use it, just specify your taglib URI to be
                <code>http://displaytag.sf.net/el</code>
                . The EL sintax is replacing the old proprietary sintax in the table "name" attribute. Note that the old
                <code>scope</code>
                and
                <code>property</code>
                attributes are no more supported in the EL version of the tag.
                <strong>EL support in this release is preliminary and it's due to change in next releases</strong>
                .
            </action>
            <action type="add" dev="mraible">
                Added to the EL taglib only a "titleKey" attribute which will lookup it's value as a key in a JSTL
                bundle (declared using the &lt;fmt:bundle tag or in your web.xml).
            </action>
            <action type="add" dev="mraible">
                Added to the EL taglib only a "url" attribute is an enhancement to the "href" attribute which prepends
                the contextPath.
            </action>
            <action type="fix" dev="fgiust" issue="902399">
                URLs now include session information for page links, sort links, urls set with "requestURI" or "href".
                Also fixes reported NPE in tomcat.
            </action>
            <action type="add" dev="fgiust" issue="879038">
                Binary releases are now compatible both with the 2.1 and 3.0 version of common-collections.
            </action>
            <action type="add" dev="fgiust" issue="917569">
                RequestHelper implementation is now configurable and can be replaced by a user-defined one. This allows
                users to plug-in specific implementations. See the configuration page and the RequestHelper javadocs for
                more info.
            </action>
            <action type="fix" dev="fgiust" issue="917200">Error in paging for URLs containing "{}".</action>
            <action type="add" dev="fgiust">
                You can now set a property value in the body of a setProperty tag, instead of using the "value"
                attribute.
            </action>
        </release>
        <release version="1.0-b2" date="December 8, 2003"
            description="b2 is mainly focused on stabilizing the new 1.0 branch">
            <action type="fix" dev="fgiust" issue="814470">Invalid xhtml if empty list.</action>
            <action type="fix" dev="fgiust" issue="749119">paging.banner.placement property.</action>
            <action type="add" dev="fgiust">
                Automatic column discovery when no columns are defined. Instead of the simple output with the object
                toString() and the message "please define column tags", the table tag will automatically add columns
                mapped to object properties. This is especially useful in development to quickly see and test available
                properties.
            </action>
            <action type="update" dev="fgiust">
                The following methods in TableDecorator are now correctly declared as
                <code>final</code>
                :
                <code>getViewIndex()</code>
                ,
                <code>getListIndex()</code>
                ,
                <code>initRow(Object, int, int)</code>
                ,
                <code>getCurrentRowObject()</code>
                . These methods should never be extended in subclasses of TableDecorator.
            </action>
            <action type="update" dev="fgiust">
                Removed the
                <code>value</code>
                property of ColumnTag. This was totally undocumented in previous versions and is now useless.
            </action>
            <action type="fix" dev="fgiust" issue="823383">Body not cleared with pooled ColumnTags.</action>
            <action type="fix" dev="fgiust" issue="814058">Sorting with table decorators.</action>
            <action type="fix" dev="fgiust" issue="830652">Parameters not preserved in requestURI.</action>
            <action type="add" dev="rapruitt">
                Added a check for availability of correct version on commons-lang: a message is displayed if a wrong
                version is used.
            </action>
            <action type="add" dev="rapruitt">
                New jsp 1.2 tld is available. Tag reference documentation is automatically produced from dtd.
            </action>
            <action type="fix" dev="fgiust" issue="814462">
                Column JSP body should not execute if the list is empty.
            </action>
            <action type="add" dev="rapruitt" issue="820763">
                Added filter (only for j2ee 1.3 containers) to allow exports from inside of an included JSP page. See
                the install docs and javadocs for more information.
            </action>
            <action type="update" dev="fgiust">Exported data is now properly escaped for the output format.</action>
            <action type="fix" dev="fgiust" issue="773162">Include header in excel export.</action>
            <action type="fix" dev="fgiust" issue="840011">Properties inheritance between table decorators.</action>
            <action type="fix" dev="rapruitt" issue="831806">
                User properties can now be loaded from files when deployed in unexploded WAR.
            </action>
            <action type="update" dev="rapruitt">
                Altered the properties search process. Properties in the file displaytag.properties will now override
                properties from TableTag.properties. Users can add additional properties via the
                TableProperties#setUserProperties() method.
            </action>
            <action type="add" dev="rapruitt">
                Added media attribute to ColumnTag. Broadened ExportTypeEnum to also cover the HTML case; renamed to
                MediaTypeEnum. Current mediaType exposed via scripting variable 'mediaType'. This can be used in column
                content to generate output based on madia type (don't output html when exporting and so on).
            </action>
        </release>
        <release version="1.0-b1" date="September 22, 2003"
            description="first beta of the completely rewritten library">
            <action type="add" dev="fgiust">
                Mavenized! Thanks to Didier Dubois for the help on migrating the build system to maven.
            </action>
            <action type="update" dev="fgiust">
                Totally refactored/rewritten. The whole library has been rewritten, improved package structure, code
                quality, logging and exception handling.
            </action>
            <action type="add" dev="fgiust">
                Major addiction: the table tag works now also with an iterator approach, letting you specify content in
                the body of the column tag.
            </action>
            <action type="update" dev="fgiust">
                Better html output. The rendered html code is now completely xhtml STRICT compliant. Some of the css
                classes have been changed, check the docs for upgrading from previous versions.
            </action>
            <action type="add" dev="fgiust">
                Global configuration with a user supplied properties file (configured in web.xml) which lets you
                personalize most of the tag output.
            </action>
            <action type="add" dev="fgiust">
                Link attributes are encoded to let you use more table in the same page with independent paging, sorting
                and exporting. You can also put nested display:table tag!
            </action>
            <action type="add" dev="fgiust">
                Link parameters are preserved in paging/sorting. Paging will always keep the correct order, and it will
                also maintain the correct order/page for all the table displayed.
            </action>
            <action type="update" dev="fgiust">Example site refactored (xhtml strict+css), added new samples.</action>
            <action type="add" dev="fgiust">
                It's now possible to define objects/nested attributes with the beanutils style language + scope (ex.
                sessionScope.list.value.attribute(name).item[1] =
                session.getAttribute("list").getValue().getAttribute("name").getItem[1]).
            </action>
            <action type="add" dev="fgiust">
                Lots of small changes/addiction:
                <ul>
                    <li>
                        renamed attributes "styleClass" to standard "class" ("styleClass" is retained but deprecated)
                    </li>
                    <li>added "defaultsort" attribute to specify the default sorted column</li>
                </ul>
            </action>
        </release>
        <release version="0.8.6" date="September 21, 2003" description="Bugfix release (fixes jre 1.3 compatibility)">
            <action type="fix" dev="" due-to="">Fixed export of full list</action>
            <action type="fix" dev="" due-to="">
                Compiled binaries are compatible with jre 1.3 (8.5 version was not working on jre 1.3 due to optimized
                1.4 compilation).
            </action>
        </release>
        <release version="0.8.5" date="March 23, 2003">
            <action type="add" dev="Luiz-Otavio Zorzella" due-to="Luiz-Otavio Zorzella">
                Allow column elements to be nested inside other tags.
            </action>
            <action type="add" dev="Luiz-Otavio Zorzella" due-to="Luiz-Otavio Zorzella">
                In decorators, added method getCollection() to allow for Collections, Iterators and Maps to be used as
                well as Lists.
            </action>
            <action type="add" dev="Luiz-Otavio Zorzella" due-to="Luiz-Otavio Zorzella">
                Original table tag only works with Lists. Now works with Collections, Iterators and Maps as well (though
                some functions, like group totals are not available to these, due to limitations on the structures
                themselves).
            </action>
            <action type="add" dev="ed-hill">
                Added startRow() to the decorator API to allow people to put headers on groupings as well as footers.
            </action>
            <action type="fix" dev="ed-hill">
                Fixed a caching bug in with tables that had multiple pages, the pageNumber is now reset to 1 in the tag
                object.
            </action>
            <action type="fix" dev="ed-hill">Fixed various with URL rewriting (? vs &amp;).</action>
            <action type="fix" dev="ed-hill">Correct error message on bean property lookups.</action>
            <action type="update" dev="mraible">Build/Deploy process updates to be more dynamic.</action>
        </release>
        <release version="0.8" date="May 25, 2002">
            <action type="add" dev="" due-to="">
                added various properties that can be override that effect the default strings and behaviors of table,
                here are some brief examples of message and behaviors that you can now set, see examples-config.jsp for
                a complete list [!!] basic.show.header - include the header at the top of the table basic.msg.empty_list
                - string displayed when there are no items to show sort.behavior - sort just viewable items, or entire
                list export.banner - message format shown in footer, you can localize export.csv - include CSV export
                option export.csv.label - name of link (localize) export.csv.include_header - include the column titles
                in the export? export.amount - export just the page of data or the complete list export.decorated -
                decorate the data as it is exported?
            </action>
            <action type="add" dev="mraible">
                introduced two new column attributes "maxLength", "maxWords" that will restrict the size of strings
                being shown in a column.
            </action>
            <action type="add" dev="" due-to="">
                introduced new column attribute "headerStyleClass" that allows you to override the class name used in
                drawing the table's header cell for that column.
            </action>
            <action type="add" dev="jay-paulsen" due-to="Jay Paulsen">
                introduced ColumnDecorators - you can now decorate individual columns, this makes it easier for you to
                define reusable DateFmt, MoneyFmt, etc... decorators rather then developing a customer decorator for
                each table. Note, the decorator interface is still not to my liking, expect changes before this tag gets
                a 1.0 release.
            </action>
            <action type="fix" dev="mraible">
                fixed a bug, where nulls were *not* being suppressed like they should be in the display, now nulls will
                only be shown if you specify the nulls attribute of the column tag.
            </action>
            <action type="fix" dev="Joachim Martin" due-to="Joachim Martin">
                fixed my web.xml files in the various wars - they were not compliant and Tomcat would barf while
                deploying them - I'm now testing under JRun 3.1/4.0 and Tomcat 4.0.4b3.
            </action>
            <action type="fix" dev="Joachim Martin" due-to="Joachim Martin">
                fixed bug in example-styles.jsp, was using a variable "page" which is a rarely used standard JSP
                variable (JRun didn't care, Tomcat did), just renamed the variable so that example runs under Tomcat.
            </action>
            <action type="add" dev="" due-to="">
                fixed bug that prevented the first column from being sorted in both ascending and descending order
            </action>
            <action type="fix" dev="" due-to="">
                fixed a problem where a decorated table would interfere with fetching the source list on subsequent
                fetches
            </action>
            <action type="fix" dev="" due-to="">
                bug was introduced in 0.7 that prevented a decorated object from being exported correctly, that has been
                fixed
            </action>
            <action type="fix" dev="" due-to="">
                bug was introduced in 0.7 that prevented a decorated object from being sorted correctly, that has been
                fixed
            </action>
            <action type="add" dev="" due-to="">
                included a copy of the Artistic license that this program is distributed under
            </action>
        </release>
        <release version="0.7" date="March 10, 2002">
            <action type="add" dev="" due-to="">
                added the requestURI attribute, so that you could tell the table tag what URI was used to call it.
            </action>
            <action type="fix" dev="" due-to="">
                fixed some exporting bugs, added the ability to export in XML, although at this stage it is very crude.
            </action>
            <action type="fix" dev="" due-to="">
                fixed sorting so that it sorts in both ascending and descending order based on multiple title clicks.
            </action>
            <action type="add" dev="" due-to="">
                updated all of the example jsp pages with a link that people can click on to view that pages source.
                Also re-organized the pages so that the example table was always at the top of the page as the first
                thing you saw, and the commentary behind the example followed.
            </action>
            <action type="fix" dev="" due-to="">
                The table tag now properly expects any decorators used to be children of the
                org.apache.taglibs.display.TableDecorator class (it was in the wrong package before). Reported by
                everyone...
            </action>
            <action type="fix" dev="mraible">
                Underscore is not a legal character in CSS, so the various style names and attributes where changes to
                be in uppercase format. - table_cell -> tableCell - table_row_odd -> tableRowOdd - table_row_even ->
                tableRowEven - table_row_action -> tableRowAction - table_cell_action -> tableCellAction -
                table_row_header -> tableRowHeader - table_cell_header -> tableCellHeader.
            </action>
            <action type="fix" dev="" due-to="">
                Cleaned up the other examples that were incomplete. Fixed broken links, etc...
            </action>
            <action type="fix" dev="Jim Canter" due-to="Jim Canter">
                Cloned the ColumnTags as I added them to the TableTag so that the table tag works correctly with web
                containers that reuse tags as an optimization. (Resin and Weblogic, probably others). This bug would
                manifest itself with multiple duplicated columns.
            </action>
            <action type="fix" dev="" due-to="">
                flushed out the example-export example that shows how to automatically export data to CSV, excel and XML
                formats.
            </action>
            <action type="fix" dev="" due-to="">
                flushed out the example-callback example that shows how to use a decorator to implement summing and
                totaling... The functionality was included in the original version, but there wasn't an example that
                showed how to use it.
            </action>
            <action type="fix" dev="" due-to="">fixed a NPE if you passed the table tag a null list.</action>
            <action type="update" dev="" due-to="">
                updated the example-grouping.jsp page to show a more report oriented example.
            </action>
            <action type="fix" dev="" due-to="Rob Evans">
                Included the pointer to the 2.2 DTD in the web.xml files.
            </action>
            <action type="update" dev="" due-to="Dirk Storck">
                added 'flush="true"' to all of my jsp:includes in my examples to be more in sync with the JSP 1.1 spec.
            </action>
        </release>
        <release version="0" date="Jan 7th, 2002" description="First public alpha feedback release">
            <action type="add" dev="" due-to="">No changes recorded prior to this release.</action>
        </release>
    </body>
</document>