<?xml version="1.0"?>
<!--
	"type" attribute can be: add, remove, update or fix. 
-->
<document>
	<properties>
		<title>Changes</title>
		<author email="fgiust AT users.sourceforge.net">Fabrizio Giustina</author>
	</properties>

	<body>

		<p>
			This file documents the changes that have been made to the display taglib. The most recently changes are
			towards the top of this file. Changes are noted using the following key:
		</p>

		<blockquote>
			<pre>
				[!] New functionality [*] Changes that are 100% backward compatible [**] Changes that requiring little
				or no modification to existing code [***] Changes requiring important modifications to existing code
			</pre>
		</blockquote>

		<release version="1.0-b1" date="September 22, 2003">
			<action type="add" dev="fgiust" due-to="Fabrizio Giustina">
				Mavenized! Thanks to Didier Dubois for the help on migrating the build system to maven.
			</action>
			<action type="update" dev="fgiust" due-to="Fabrizio Giustina">
				Totally refactored/rewritten. The whole library has been rewritten, improved package structure, code
				quality, logging and exception handling.
			</action>
			<action type="add" dev="fgiust" due-to="Fabrizio Giustina">
				Major addiction: the table tag works now also with an iterator approach, letting you specify content in
				the body of the column tag.
			</action>
			<action type="update" dev="fgiust" due-to="Fabrizio Giustina">
				Better html output. The rendered html code is now completely xhtml STRICT compliant. Some of the css
				classes have been changed, check the docs for upgrading from previous versions.
			</action>
			<action type="add" dev="fgiust" due-to="Fabrizio Giustina">
				Global configuration with a user supplied properties file (configured in web.xml) which lets you
				personalize most of the tag output.
			</action>
			<action type="add" dev="fgiust" due-to="Fabrizio Giustina">
				Link attributes are encoded to let you use more table in the same page with indipendent paging, sorting
				and exporting. You can also put nested display:table tag!
			</action>
			<action type="add" dev="fgiust" due-to="Fabrizio Giustina">
				Link parameters are preserved in paging/sorting. Paging will always keep the correct order, and it will
				also mantain the correct order/page for all the table displayed.
			</action>
			<action type="update" dev="fgiust" due-to="Fabrizio Giustina">
				Example site refactored (xhtml strict+css), added new samples.
			</action>
			<action type="add" dev="fgiust" due-to="Fabrizio Giustina">
				It's now possible to define objects/nested attributes with the beanutils style language + scope (ex.
				sessionScope.list.value.attribute(name).item[1] =
				session.getAttribute("list").getValue().getAttribute("name").getItem[1])
			</action>
			<action type="add" dev="fgiust" due-to="Fabrizio Giustina">
				Lots of small changes/addiction:
				<ul>
					<li>
						renamed attributes "styleClass" to standard "class" ("styleClass" is keeped but deprecated)
					</li>
					<li>added "defaultsort" attribute to specify the default sorted column</li>
				</ul>
			</action>
		</release>

		<release version="0.8.5" date="March 23, 2003">
			<action type="add" dev="Luiz-Otavio Zorzella" due-to="Luiz-Otavio Zorzella">
				Allow column elements to be nested inside other tags. [!]
			</action>
			<action type="add" dev="Luiz-Otavio Zorzella" due-to="Luiz-Otavio Zorzella">
				In decorators, added method getCollection() to allow for Collections, Iterators and Maps to be used as
				well as Lists. [!]
			</action>
			<action type="add" dev="Luiz-Otavio Zorzella" due-to="Luiz-Otavio Zorzella">
				Original table tag only works with Lists. Now works with Collections, Iterators and Maps as well
				(though some functions, like group totals are not available to these, due to limitations on the
				structures themselves). [!]
			</action>
			<action type="add" dev="ed-hill" due-to="Ed Hill">
				Added startRow() to the decorator API to allow people to put headers on groupings as well as footers.
				[!]
			</action>
			<action type="fix" dev="ed-hill" due-to="Ed Hill">
				Fixed a caching bug in with tables that had multiple pages, the pageNumber is now reset to 1 in the tag
				object. [*]
			</action>
			<action type="fix" dev="ed-hill" due-to="Ed Hill">Fixed various with URL rewriting (? vs &amp;). [*]</action>
			<action type="fix" dev="ed-hill" due-to="Ed Hill">
				Correct error message on bean property lookups. [*]
			</action>
			<action type="update" dev="mraible" due-to="Matt Raible">
				Build/Deploy process updates to be more dynamic. [*]
			</action>
		</release>

		<release version="0.8" date="May 25, 2002">

			<action type="add" dev="" due-to="">
				added various properties that can be override that effect the default strings and behaviors of table,
				here are some brief examples of message and behaviors that you can now set, see examples-config.jsp for
				a complete list [!!] basic.show.header - include the header at the top of the table
				basic.msg.empty_list - string displayed when there are no items to show sort.behavior - sort just
				viewable items, or entire list export.banner - message format shown in footer, you can localize
				export.csv - include CSV export option export.csv.label - name of link (localize)
				export.csv.include_header - include the column titles in the export? export.amount - export just the
				page of data or the complete list export.decorated - decorate the data as it is exported?
			</action>

			<action type="add" dev="mraible" due-to="Matt Raible">
				introduced two new column attributes "maxLength", "maxWords" that will restrict the size of strings
				being shown in a column. [!]
			</action>

			<action type="add" dev="" due-to="">
				introduced new column attribute "headerStyleClass" that allows you to override the class name used in
				drawing the table's header cell for that column. [!]
			</action>

			<action type="add" dev="jay-paulsen" due-to="Jay Paulsen">
				introduced ColumnDecorators - you can now decorate individual columns, this makes it easier for you to
				define reuable DateFmt, MoneyFmt, etc... decorators rather then developing a customer decorator for
				each table. Note, the decorator inteface is still not to my liking, expect changes before this tag gets
				a 1.0 release. [!]
			</action>

			<action type="fix" dev="mraible" due-to="Matt Raible" due-to-email="mraible@users.sourceforge.net">
				fixed a bug, where nulls were *not* being surpressed like they should be in the display, now nulls will
				only be shown if you specify the nulls attribute of the column tag. [**]
			</action>

			<action type="fix" dev="Joachim Martin" due-to="Joachim Martin">
				fixed my web.xml files in the various wars - they were not compliant and Tomcat would barf while
				deploying them - I'm now testing under JRun 3.1/4.0 and Tomcat 4.0.4b3. [*]
			</action>

			<action type="fix" dev="Joachim Martin" due-to="Joachim Martin">
				fixed bug in example-styles.jsp, was using a variable "page" which is a rarely used standard JSP
				variable (JRun didn't care, Tomcat did), just renamed the variable so that example runs under Tomcat.
				[*]
			</action>

			<action type="add" dev="" due-to="">
				fixed bug that prevented the first column from being sorted in both ascending and descending order [*]
			</action>

			<action type="fix" dev="" due-to="">
				fixed a problem where a decorated table would interfere with fetching the source list on subsequent
				fetches [*]
			</action>

			<action type="fix" dev="" due-to="">
				bug was introduced in 0.7 that prevented a decorated object from being exported correctly, that has
				been fixed [*]
			</action>

			<action type="fix" dev="" due-to="">
				bug was introduced in 0.7 that prevented a decorated object from being sorted correctly, that has been
				fixed [*]
			</action>

			<action type="add" dev="" due-to="">
				included a copy of the Artistic license that this program is distributed under [*]
			</action>
		</release>

		<release version="0.7" date="March 10, 2002">

			<action type="add" dev="" due-to="">
				added the requestURI attribute, so that you could tell the table tag what URI was used to call it. [!]
			</action>
			<action type="fix" dev="" due-to="">
				fixed some exporting bugs, added the ability to export in XML, although at this stage it is very crude.
				[!]
			</action>
			<action type="fix" dev="" due-to="">
				fixed sorting so that it sorts in both ascending and decending order based on multiple title clicks. [!]
			</action>
			<action type="add" dev="" due-to="">
				updated all of the example jsp pages with a link that people can click on to view that pages source.
				Also re-orged the pages so that the example table was always at the top of the page as the first thing
				you saw, and the commentary behind the example followed. [!]
			</action>
			<action type="fix" dev="" due-to="">
				The table tag now properly expects any decorators used to be children of the
				org.apache.taglibs.display.TableDecorator class (it was in the wrong package before). Reported by
				everyone... [**]
			</action>
			<action type="fix" dev="mraible" due-to="Matt Raible" due-to-email="mraible@users.sourceforge.net">
				Underscore is not a legal character in CSS, so the various style names and attributes where changes to
				be in upcase format. - table_cell -> tableCell - table_row_odd -> tableRowOdd - table_row_even ->
				tableRowEven - table_row_action -> tableRowAction - table_cell_action -> tableCellAction -
				table_row_header -> tableRowHeader - table_cell_header -> tableCellHeader. [**]
			</action>
			<action type="fix" dev="" due-to="">
				Cleaned up the other examples that were incomplete. Fixed broken links, etc... [*]
			</action>
			<action type="fix" dev="Jim Canter" due-to="Jim Canter">
				Cloned the ColumnTags as I added them to the TableTag so that the table tag works correctly with web
				containers that reuse tags as an optimization. (Resin and Weblogic, probably others). This bug would
				manifest itself with multiple duplicated columns. [*]
			</action>
			<action type="fix" dev="" due-to="">
				flushed out the example-export example that shows how to automatically export data to CSV, excel and
				XML formats. [*]
			</action>
			<action type="fix" dev="" due-to="">
				flushed out the example-callback example that shows how to use a decorator to implement summing and
				totalling... The functionality was included in the original version, but there wasn't an example that
				showed how to use it. [*]
			</action>
			<action type="fix" dev="" due-to="">fixed a NPE if you passed the table tag a null list. [*]</action>
			<action type="update" dev="" due-to="">
				updated the example-grouping.jsp page to show a more report oriented example. [*]
			</action>
			<action type="fix" dev="" due-to="">
				Included the pointer to the 2.2 DTD in the web.xml files. Thanks to Rob Evans. [*]
			</action>
			<action type="update" dev="" due-to="">
				added 'flush="true"' to all of my jsp:includes in my examples to be more in sync with the JSP 1.1 spec.
				Thanks to Dirk Storck [*]
			</action>
		</release>

		<release version="First public alpha feedback release" date="Jan 7th, 2002">

			<action type="add" dev="" due-to="">No changes recorded prior to this release.</action>
		</release>

	</body>
</document>
