<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<document>
  <properties>
    <title>Overview</title>
    <author email="fgiust AT users.sourceforge.net">Fabrizio Giustina</author>
  </properties>
  <body>
    <section name="Overview">
      <p>The display tag library is an open source suite of custom tags that provide high level web presentation patterns which will work in an MVC model. The library provides a significant amount of functionality while still being simple and straight-forward to use.</p>
    </section>
    <section name="What's New">
      <subsection name="January 3, 2004">
        <p>
          Snapshot builds are now available. See <a href="download.html">download</a> for details.
          Also check the nice <a href="statcvs/index.html">statcvs</a> reports, I finally managed to make
          this maven plugin working...
        </p>
      </subsection>
      <subsection name="December 30, 2003">
        <p>
          Started working on 1.0-b3 release. The site is always updated with
          the latest changes, so be sure to refer to the docs included in the
          distribution zip for previous releases.
          We will try to make nightly build available shortly.
        </p>
      </subsection>
      <subsection name="December 8, 2003">
        <p>
          1.0-b2 is finally out! Check out
          <a href="changes-report.html">changes</a>
          for details about new features and fixed bugs and
          <a href="download.html">download the distribution here</a>
          .
        </p>
        <p>
          Note that the b2 version now requires j2ee 1.3 to compile, but it still runs on any j2ee 1.2 container. The new
          <a href="apidocs/org/displaytag/filter/ResponseOverrideFilter.html">export filter</a>
          (fixes exporting with includes or struts tiles) can only be used on 1.3 containers.
        </p>
      </subsection>
    </section>
    <section name="What can I do with it?">
      <p>Actually the display tag library can just... display tables! Give it a list of objects and it will handle column display, sorting, paging, cropping, grouping, exporting, smart linking and decoration of the table in a nice and customizable xhtml style.</p>
      <p>This is a sample of tables generated from lists using the &lt;display:table&gt; tag:</p>
      <img src="images/sample_snapshot.png" width="562" height="543" alt="sample tables produced with the display:table tag" />
    </section>
  </body>
</document>

