<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<document>
  <properties>
    <title>Displaytag tutorial</title>
    <author email="fgiust(at)users.sourceforge.net">Fabrizio Giustina</author>
  </properties>
  <body>
    <section name="Simplest case, no columns">
      
  <source><![CDATA[

<% request.setAttribute( "test", new TestList(10, false) ); %>

<display:table name="test" />

]]></source>

      <img src="images/tut_basic.png" width="402" height="137" alt="basic table" />
      
      <p>
        The simplest possible usage of the table tag is to point the table tag at a java.util.List 
        implementation and do nothing else. The table tag will iterate through the list and display 
        a column for each property contained in the objects.
      </p>
      <p>
        Typically, the only time that you would want to use the tag in this simple way would be during development 
        as a sanity check. For production, you should always define at least a single column.
      </p>

      
    </section>
    
    
    <section name="Basic, columns">
    
<source><![CDATA[

<% request.setAttribute( "test", new TestList(10, false) ); %>

<display:table name="test">
  <display:column property="id" title="ID" />
  <display:column property="name" />
  <display:column property="email" />
  <display:column property="status" />
  <display:column property="description" title="Comments"/>
</display:table>

]]></source>

    <img src="images/tut_columns.png" width="566" height="214" alt="table - columns" />
    
    <p>
      This example starts to show you how to use the table tag.  You point the table tag at
      a datasource (a List), then define a number of columns with properties that map to
      accessor methods (getXXX) for each object in the List.
    </p>
    
    <p>
      Note that you have one column tag for every column that you want to appear in
      the table.  And, the column specifies what property is shown in that particular
      row.
    </p>
    
    <p>
      You can define the content of a column by adding a <code>property</code> attribute
      to the column tag or adding a content to the tag.
    </p>
    
    <ul>
      <li><![CDATA[<display:column property="email" />]]></li>
      <li><![CDATA[<display:column title="email">email@it.com</display:column>]]></li>
    </ul>

    <p>
      There are two ways to define the content of a column. Of course, in the tag body
      you can use scriptlets or other custom tags.
      Using the <code>property</code> attribute to define the content of a column is
      usually faster and works better with sorting. If you add a <code>property</code>
      attribute the tag body is ignored.
    </p>
    <p>
      Adding content in the column body you can easily concatenate or "decorate" fields available in objects in the list.
			See the <a href="tut_implicitobjects.html">implicit objects</a> chapter for more details.
    </p>
    <p>
      The <code>property</code> attribute specifies what <code>getXXX</code> method is 
      called on each item in the list.  
      So for the second column, <code>getName</code> is called.  By default the 
      property name is used as the header of the column unless you explicitly give the column 
      a title.
    </p>
    </section>

    
    
  </body>
</document>

