<?xml version="1.0"?>
<document>

    <properties>
        <title>Directory organization</title>
        <author email="fgiust AT users.sourceforge.net">Fabrizio Giustina</author>
    </properties>

    <body>

        <section name="Overview">
            <p>
				The display tag library uses Maven for build and documentation and tries to conform to general Maven
				project layout. If you are used to working on a maven-driven project you should feel comfortable with it.
				Here is a description of the file and folder organization.  The
                <strong>strong</strong>	names refer to project specific setting/files.
            </p>
        </section>
        <section name="Common Directory Layout">
            <table>
                <tr>
                    <th>Directory or file name</th>
                    <th>Content</th>
                    <th>Comment</th>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    <td>LICENSE.txt</td>
                    <td>The license for the project.</td>
                    <td>
						This file contains the license that applies to the project.
                    </td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    <td>project.xml</td>
                    <td>Maven project descriptor</td>
                    <td>
						This file contains the basic project configuration for maven (project name, developers, urls,
						dependencies, etc).
                    </td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    <td>project.properties</td>
                    <td>A file defining project specific properties.</td>
                    <td>
							This file can be used to override maven default properties for the core and properties for
							the various plugins.

							It can also be used to define any maven properties used by a project. The properties
							defined in this file should be applicable to most users of your project, as opposed to
							custom properties for a specific build/user which should be defined in
                        <code>${project.home}/build.properties</code>
							.
                    </td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    <td>maven.xml</td>
                    <td>Maven configuration for defining build goals</td>
                    <td>
						This file contains the default maven goals for the project, plus added pre-post operations to be
						performed.
                    </td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    <td>src/</td>
                    <td>Source code</td>
                    <td>
						This is the main directory for all the source code, subdivided in subdirectory to separate
						different "kind" of code.
                    </td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    <td>
                        <strong>src/java</strong>
                    </td>
                    <td>Java source code</td>
                    <td>
						This directory contains all the java source code both for the library and the example webapp.
                    </td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    <td>
                        <strong>src/webapp</strong>
                    </td>
                    <td>Example webapp source</td>
                    <td>
						This directory contains all the code (JSP, images, web.xml configuration) for the example
						webapp.
                    </td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    <td>
                        <strong>src/tld</strong>
                    </td>
                    <td>tld</td>
                    <td>
						This directory contains the tag library definition file (tld), which is
						added in the library jar and in the examples war during the build.
                    </td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    <td>xdocs/</td>
                    <td>Documentation files in XML format.</td>
                    <td>
						Maven projects use Jelly/JSL to transform documentation files in XML into HTML. Project
						documentation should be placed in this directory. Maven converts all XML files in this
						directory using JSL. Non-XML files (and directories) are copied without modification to permit
						the inclusion of "other" types of documentation (including images). The generated HTML files
						automatically inherit the Maven look-and-feel by default.
                    </td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    <td>xdocs/navigation.xml</td>
                    <td>Navigation links for site.</td>
                    <td>
						Maven projects use Jelly stylesheets to transform documentation files in XML into HTML (XHTML
						for the most part). This file includes the navigation links that are added to each xdoc
						transformed in the
                        <code>xdocs</code>
						directory.
                    </td>
                </tr>

                <tr>
                    <td>
                        <strong>checkstyle.xml</strong>
                    </td>
                    <td>Checkstyle configuration file</td>
                    <td>Configuration file containing checkstyle settings used during generation of reports.</td>
                </tr>
            </table>
        </section>
        <section name="Maven-Generated Layout">
            <table>
                <tr>
                    <th>Directory name</th>
                    <th>Content</th>
                    <th>Comment</th>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    <td>target/</td>
                    <td>Contains compiled classes and JARs.</td>
                    <td>
						The contents of the target/ directory should be enough to use the project. This directory
						contains the final JAR and WAR that are generated.
                    </td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    <td>target/classes</td>
                    <td>Contains compiled classes.</td>
                    <td>
						The target/classes directory contains all compiled classes. This directory is used when
						packaging the final JAR for a project.
                    </td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    <td>target/generated-docs</td>
                    <td>Contains Maven generated xdocs.</td>
                    <td>
						The target/generated-docs directory contains all of the Maven-generated xdocs. All content
						generated by Maven is first converted to xdoc format, so the same stylesheet used to transform
						the rest of the site can be used on generated content. The contents of this directory are
						transformed and stored in the docs/ directory.
                    </td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    <td>target/docs</td>
                    <td>Documentation files intended for the website publication.</td>
                    <td>
						The docs/ directory contains only generated documentation that is intended to be published as
						the project's website. This directory includes the Velocity/DVSL generated HTML files,
						JavaDocs, cross-referenced sources, and various generated reports. Generally, all documentation
						is stored in the xdocs/ directory and then "transformed" into this directory. The specific
						documents that Maven generates are described below.
                    </td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    <td>target/docs/index.html</td>
                    <td>Starting point for browsing the documentation.</td>
                    <td>
						Browsing the documentation locally should yield the same results as browsing the documentation
						on the project's home page.
                    </td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    <td>target/docs/apidocs</td>
                    <td>API documentation.</td>
                    <td>
						Maven automatically generates JavaDocs for projects using the JavaDoc utility. Placing the API
						documentation under docs/apidocs/ makes it slightly easier for other documentation files under
						docs/ to reference API documentation and vice versa.
                    </td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    <td>target/docs/xref</td>
                    <td>Cross-referenced source code.</td>
                    <td>
						Maven automatically generates cross-referenced source code that enables easy browsing of an
						entire source tree. Placing the cross-referenced sources under docs/xref/ makes it slightly
						easier for other documentation files under docs/ to reference API documentation and vice versa.
                    </td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    <td>target/docs/mail-lists.html</td>
                    <td>Mailing list documentation.</td>
                    <td>
						Maven automatically generates a list of mailing lists based on the information provided in the
						project descriptor.
                    </td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    <td>target/docs/team-list.html</td>
                    <td>The list of project team members.</td>
                    <td>
						Maven automatically generates a list of project team members based on the information provided
						in the project descriptor.
                    </td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    <td>target/docs/dependencies.html</td>
                    <td>The list of dependencies.</td>
                    <td>
						Maven automatically generates a list of dependencies based on the information provided in the
						project descriptor.
                    </td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    <td>target/docs/changelog.html</td>
                    <td>The CVS change log.</td>
                    <td>
						Maven automatically generates a change log from CVS log messages. This log is currently limited
						to the past 30 days (but will be configurable in the future).
                    </td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    <td>target/docs/file-activity-report.html</td>
                    <td>The File Activity Report.</td>
                    <td>
						Maven automatically generates a log from your SCM listing file changes in the last 30 days.
                    </td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    <td>target/docs/developer-activity-report.html</td>
                    <td>The Developer Activity Report.</td>
                    <td>
						Maven automatically generates a log from your SCM listing changes per developer in the last 30
						days.
                    </td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    <td>target/docs/jdepend-report.html</td>
                    <td>Metric report.</td>
                    <td>
						Maven automatically generates a report on various source code metrics. This report can provide
						further insight into a project.
                    </td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    <td>target/docs/checkstyle-report.html</td>
                    <td>Checkstyle report.</td>
                    <td>
						Maven automatically generates a report on the results of Checkstyle. This report provides
						assurance that the coding conventions for your project are being followed.
                    </td>
                </tr>
            </table>
        </section>
    </body>
</document>
