<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<document>
    <properties>
        <title>Exporting</title>
        <author email="fgiust(at)users.sourceforge.net">Fabrizio Giustina</author>
    </properties>
    <body>
        <section name="Exporting data">


            <p>
                When you set the Table Tag's
                <strong>export</strong>
                attribute to "true", a footer will appear below the table which will allow you to export the data being
                shown in various formats.
            </p>
            <p>
                Displaytag includes a few ready made
                <em>export views</em>
                which allow you to export data in CSV, excel,  and XML format. A simple PDF export view is also available.
                The following table lists the predefined export options included in displaytag distribution.
            </p>

            <table>
                <thead>
                    <tr>
                        <th>Media</th>
                        <th>Export View Class</th>
                        <th>Description</th>
                    </tr>
                </thead>
                <tbody>
                    <tr>
                        <td>CSV</td>
                        <td class="code">org.displaytag.export.CsvView</td>
                        <td>Export to comma separated list</td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td>Excel</td>
                        <td class="code">org.displaytag.export.ExcelView</td>
                        <td>Export to excel - ascii format, tab separated</td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td>XML</td>
                        <td class="code">org.displaytag.export.XmlView</td>
                        <td>Simple xml output</td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td>PDF</td>
                        <td class="code">org.displaytag.export.PdfView</td>
                        <td>
                            Sample PDF export view. This is not enabled by default in the distribution but can be
                            enabled by setting
                            <code>export.pdf=true</code>
                            in displaytag.properties and including the required IText dependency (see
                            <a href="dependencies.html">displaytag dependencies</a>
                            ). Since you probably want to tweak the layout of your pdf output, this is probably more
                            useful as a base reference for creating your own PDF export view.
                        </td>
                    </tr>
                </tbody>
            </table>

        </section>

        <section name="Configuring export and export views">
            <p>
                The
                <code>export.types</code>
                parameter contains the list of registered export views. For each export type you can configure other
                parameters: see the
                <code>
                    export.
                    <em>exportname</em>.*
                </code>
                parameters in
                <a href="configuration.html">configuration</a>
                .
            </p>
            <p>
                You can enable/disable a specific export type using the
                <code>
                    export.
                    <em>exportname</em>.enabled
                </code>
                parameter.
            </p>
            <p>
                If you don't want some column to show during export (or you only want them to show during export) you
                can use the column
                <code>media</code>
                attribute (see tag reference for more details).
            </p>


        </section>

        <section name="Adding a new Export view">
            <ol>
                <li>
                    Write your own exportView class. You need to implement the
                    <code>org.displaytag.export.TextExportView</code>
                    or
                    <code>org.displaytag.export.BinaryExportView</code>
                    interface. You can look at the
                    <a href="xref/org/displaytag/export/PdfView.html">sample binary PDF export view</a>
                    or to
                    <a href="xref/org/displaytag/export/BaseExportView.html">
                        the base text export view used by displaytag
                    </a>
                    .
                </li>
                <li>
                    Add a
                    <code>displaytag.properties</code>
                    file in your application classpath (if you already don't have one) and add the name of your export
                    media along with the default ones to the export type parameter:
                    <source>
                        <![CDATA[
export.types=csv excel xml [mymedia]
                        ]]>
                    </source>
                </li>
                <li>
                    Always in
                    <code>displaytag.properties</code>
                    , add the following properties:
                    <source>
                        <![CDATA[
export.[mymedia]=true
                     
export.[mymedia].class=fully.qualified.class.name
 
export.[mymedia].label=Click here to try my export

# include header parameter is forwarded to your export view
export.[mymedia].include_header=true
                     
# if set, file is downloaded instead of opened in the browser window
export.[mymedia].filename=
                        ]]>
                    </source>
                </li>
                <li>
                    Try it. You should see a new link with the text you added to
                    <code>
                        export.
                        <em>mymedia</em>
                        .label
                    </code>
                    . Clicking on it will invoke your Export view.  You should see the results in your browser.
                </li>
            </ol>
        </section>

        <section name="Text/Binary export views">
            <p>
                Common displaytag export options (CSV, Xml and Excel) output a simple text-based format. Other file
                formats require binary content, like the sample PDF included with the distribution.
            </p>
            <p>
                Exporting binary data from a JSP is a bit tricky, since JSPs are only designed to output characters: as
                a starting point keep in mind that
                <strong>binary export is not assured to work on every application server</strong>
                , at least without the help of an external filter (see
                <a href="export_filter.html">export filter</a>
                ).
            </p>
            <p>
                It may work without a filter if your application server allows JSPs to call
                <code>response.getOutputStream()</code>
                , but this method really shouldn't be used in JSPs.  Using an the export filter, especially in buffered
                mode, could solve the problem, since the output stream is requested by the filter outside the JSP.
            </p>
        </section>

    </body>
</document>

