<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<document>
    <properties>
        <title>Decorators</title>
        <author email="fgiust(at)users.sourceforge.net">Fabrizio Giustina</author>
    </properties>
    <body>
        <section name="Decorators">
            <p>
                A "decorator" is a design pattern where one object provides a layer of functionality by wrapping or
                "decorating" another object.
            </p>
            <subsection name="Table decorators">
                <source>
                    <![CDATA[
<display:table name="test" decorator="org.displaytag.sample.Wrapper" >
  <display:column property="id" title="ID" />
  <display:column property="email" />
  <display:column property="status" />
  <display:column property="date" />
  <display:column property="money" />
</display:table>
]]>
                </source>

                <p>
                    Let's assume you have list of business objects that you want to display, and the objects contain
                    properties that don't return native Strings, and you want control over how they get displayed in the
                    list (for example, Dates, money, numbers, etc...). I would be bad form to put this type of
                    formatting code inside your business objects, so instead create a Decorator that formats the data
                    according to your needs.
                </p>

                <p>
                    Notice the following 4 key things (and refer to the TableDecorator javadoc for some of the other
                    details).
                </p>

                <ul>
                    <li>
                        The Wrapper class must be a subclass of TableDecorator. There is various bootstrapping and API
                        methods that are called inside the TableDecorator class and your class must subclass it for
                        things to work properly (you will get a JspException if your class does not subclass it).
                    </li>
                    <li>
                        Be smart and create your formatters just once in the constructor method - performance will be a
                        lot better...
                    </li>
                    <li>
                        Notice how the getDate() and getMoney() methods overload the return value of your business
                        object contained in the List. They use the
                        <code>TableDecorator.getCurrentRowObject()</code>
                        method to get a handle to the underlying business object, and then format it accordingly.
                    </li>
                    <li>
                        We do not have to overload each of the other business object properties (like getID, getEmail,
                        etc...). The decorator class is called first, but if it doesn't implement the method for the
                        property called, then the underlying business class is called.
                    </li>
                </ul>

                <p>
                    The way this works is that a single decorator object is created right before the table tag starts
                    iterating through your List, before it starts processing a particular row, it gives the object for
                    that row to the decorator, then as the various properties getXXX() methods - the decorator will be
                    called first and if the decorator doesn't implement the given property, the method will be called on
                    the original object in your List.
                </p>

            </subsection>
            <subsection name="Column Decorators">

                <p>
                    You can also specify decorators that work on individual columns, this would allow you to come up
                    with data specific formatters, and just reuse them rather then coming up with a custom decorator for
                    each table that you want to show a formatted date for.
                </p>

                <source>
                    <![CDATA[
<display:table name="test">
  <display:column property="id" title="ID" />
  <display:column property="email" />
  <display:column property="status" />
  <display:column property="date" decorator="org.displaytag.sample.LongDateWrapper" />
</display:table>
]]>
                </source>

            </subsection>
            <subsection name="Table decorators, column decorators or code in the column body?">
                <p>
                    As a rule of thumb, a decorator is faster than using scriptlet or custom tags in the column body
                    when using paging. When the column body is filled and full list is sorted, all the records need to
                    be "prepared" by the table tag iterating on the whole list. If the column body is used the content
                    will be evaluated for any row, also for the non displayed ones; using
                    <code>property</code>
                    , on the other hand, will cause the decorator only to be called for displayed rows.
                </p>
                <p>
                    A table decorator have the power to add extra properties to your objects: for example you can add a
                    <code>getFullAddress()</code>
                    method to your table decorator and then use
                    <code>property="fullAddress"</code>
                    in a column. A table decorator can also provide custom html code added at the beginning/end of rowss
                    and table.
                </p>
                <p>
                    A column decorator is rather limited in its funcionality: it simply format an available value, and
                    has actually no access to the page context or other properties. However, it is the simplest and most
                    reusable block if you simply need to format dates, number or custom strings.
                </p>
                <p>
                    Leaving decorators out and filling the column body is the simplest solution if you don't have to
                    worry too much about paging and performance and it is optimal in a small, non paged, table. During
                    sorting, though, if the column body is used, the result will be always sorted as a String.
                </p>
            </subsection>
        </section>
    </body>
</document>

