<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<document>
    <properties>
        <title>Overview</title>
        <author email="fgiust(at)users.sourceforge.net">Fabrizio Giustina</author>
    </properties>
    <body>
        <section name="Overview">
            <p>
                The display tag library is an open source suite of custom tags that provide high-level web presentation
                patterns which will work in an MVC model. The library provides a significant amount of functionality
                while still being easy to use.
            </p>
        </section>
        <section name="News">
            <subsection name="October, 2004">
                <p>
                    <p>
                        Problems and wishes reported against the previous display tag release are now tracked in the
                        <a href="http://jira.codehaus.org/browse/DISPL">Displaytag Jira Tracker</a>
                        at Codehaus.
                    </p>
                    <p>
                        Current development is focused on removing limitations and design flaws.
                    </p>
                    <ul>
                        <li>
                            Do you want to add a new export type? You can now do that, it is configurable!
                            And, a PDF export sample has also been added.
                        </li>
                        <li>
                            Do you want to easily i18n display tag properties?  Yes, display tag will support it, and you
                            also can configure the way the locale is choosen.
                        </li>
                        <li>
                            Do you want to use i18n in column titles in the non-EL version of the taglib, or use an i18n
                            support other than JSTL? You will be free to plug-in your own
                            <code>I18nResourceProvider</code>!
                        </li>
                    </ul>
                    <p>
                        A <a href="http://jira.codehaus.org/secure/BrowseProject.jspa?id=10800&amp;report=roadmap">
                            roadmap
                        </a>
                        where issues are scheduled and prioritized is available on JIRA. Login is required.  You are
                        free to create an account.
                    </p>
                    <p>
                        <strong>
                            This documentation corresponds to the latest development snapshot (unreleased version).
                            Refer to the documentation included in your download if you are using a previous release.
                        </strong>
                    </p>
                </p>
            </subsection>
        </section>
        <section name="What can I do with it?">
            <p>
                Actually the display tag library can just... display tables! Give it a list of objects and it will
                handle column display, sorting, paging, cropping, grouping, exporting, smart linking and decoration of
                a table in a customizable XHTML style.
            </p>
            <p>The tables in the sample images below were generated from lists using the &lt;display:table&gt; tag:</p>
            <img src="images/sample_snapshot.png" width="562" height="543"
                alt="sample tables produced with the display:table tag" />
        </section>
    </body>
</document>