<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<document>
    <properties>
        <title>Issue tracking</title>
        <author email="fgiust(at)users.sourceforge.net">Fabrizio Giustina</author>
    </properties>
    <body>
        <section name="Issue Tracking ">
            <p>
                Go to
                <a href="http://jira.codehaus.org/browse/DISPL">Displaytag bug and feature request tracker (JIRA)</a>
                to see open bugs or to submit new requests.
            </p>
            <p>
                Please note that the issue tracker on sourceforge is not used anymore and any remaining item will be
                moved to the new tracker.
            </p>
        </section>
        <section name="Bug reporting">
            <p>
                Before submitting a bug to the
                <a href="http://jira.codehaus.org/browse/DISPL">JIRA</a> above, please be sure you have done your homework.  This includes:
            </p>
            <ol>
                <li>Reading the
                    <a href="faq.html">FAQ</a> to understand the correct behavior
                </li>
                <li>Searching the JIRA for a comparable issue; you may not be the first person to find this bug</li>
                <li>Searching the user list archives if you are not sure the behavior you are experiencing is a bug</li>
            </ol>
            <p>
                Post help requests to the user mailing list.
            </p>
            <p>
                <strong>Please do not post bug reports or patches directly to the user or development mailing lists !</strong>
                Always submit them to the JIRA before.  This will help us track and review them. After
                submitting a bug, you are free to discuss it in the developer mailing list (without attaching code or
                patches to mails).
            </p>
        </section>
        <section name="Feature requests and patches for new features">
            <p>As always, use the JIRA to submit feature requests (in the RFE category).</p>
            <p>
                If you have modified your local version of the display tag library by adding a new feature and would like to see in the main distribution, open
                a new RFE (Request For Enhancement) in the JIRA and attach the patch to it (
                <strong>don't send it to the mailing list</strong>
                ).
            </p>
            <p>
                If you want to see your patch quickly applied by committers, you should be able to provide the
                following items:
            </p>
            <ol>
                <li>
                    A CVS diff against the latest CVS version.
                    <strong>No, a zip file with all modified sources is not OK</strong>.
                </li>
                <li>
                    One or more junit tests related to the new feature. Also, be sure to run all of the existing testcases
                    to verify that you are not breaking existing code. Look in the src/test directory to understand
                    how to write simple JSP test cases.
                </li>
                <li>Update the documentation (xdoc files and/or the sample application).</li>
            </ol>
            <p>
                If all of these requirements are met, your patch will likely be accepted soon.  If you only provide a zip
                with the modified source files; keep in mind that before your addition can be committed to CVS, a developer must complete all of the other tasks
                <i>for you</i>.
                This could take a long time.
            </p>
        </section>
    </body>
</document>

