<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<document>
    <properties>
        <title>Issue tracking</title>
        <author email="fgiust(at)users.sourceforge.net">Fabrizio Giustina</author>
    </properties>
    <body>
        <section name="Issue Tracking ">
            <p>
                Go to
                <a href="http://sourceforge.net/tracker/?group_id=73068">SourceForge bug and feature request tracker</a>
                to see open bugs or to submit new requests.
            </p>
        </section>
        <section name="Bug reporting">
            <p>
                Please report any found bug in the tracker above. Check carefully that the same item is not already
                listed in existing bugs.
            </p>
            <p>
                Please read faqs and mailing list archives before if you are not sure if a behaviour is a bug and if you
                are using displaytag in the correct way. Post any help request to the
                <strong>user</strong>
                mailing list.
            </p>
            <p>
                <strong>Please do not post bug reports or patches to mailing lists directly!</strong>
                Always submit them to the bug tracker before, this will help us to track and review them. After
                submitting an item, you are free to discuss it in the develper mailing list (without attaching code or
                patches to mails).
            </p>
        </section>
        <section name="Feature requests and patches for new features">
            <p>As always, use the tracker to submit any feature request (in the RFE category).</p>
            <p>
                If you modify the tag library adding a new feature you would like to see in the main distribution, open
                a new RFE and attach the patch to it (
                <strong>don't sent it to the mailing list</strong>
                ).
            </p>
            <p>
                If you want to see your patch applied by committers in a short time you should be able to provide the
                following items:
            </p>
            <ol>
                <li>
                    A cvs diff against the latest cvs version (no, a zip file with all the modified sources is not ok)
                </li>
                <li>
                    One or more junit test which tests your new feature. Also be sure to run all the existing testcases
                    to be sure that you are not going to break anything. Look in the src/test directory to understand
                    how to write simple jsp testcases.
                </li>
                <li>Update documentation (xdoc files and/or sample application).</li>
            </ol>
            <p>
                If all these requirements are met, you patch will be probably accepted soon. If you only provide a zip
                with the modified files keep in mind that a developer should complete all the other tasks for you before
                committing any change to cvs, and this could require a long time.
            </p>
        </section>
    </body>
</document>

